Contact

+60149337280 (Home) skuhandran@yahoo.com

www.linkedin.com/in/kuhandransamudrapandiyan (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

System Implementations
Project Plans
Information Technology

Languages

Tamil (Native or Bilingual)
English (Professional Working)
Sinhalese (Limited Working)

Certifications

Building Scalable Java Microservices with Spring Boot and Spring Cloud

Developing and Deploying Microservices with Microclimate

5 hours of full JavaScript & ES6 (Including ES7 & React JS)

IBM Microservices - Fundamentals
Certified ScrumMaster (CSM)

Honors-Awards

CodeFest 3.0, 150 Students Compete in 24 Hours Hackathon IFLIX/Hack (Jom Hack) ICT Project Trade Show 2017 -Highly Commended Project

Kuhandran SamudraPandiyan

Incident Support Managment | Project Manager | Senior System Analyst (Assistant Manager)|Senior Software Engineer | Front-End Technology Specialist (HTML, CSS, JavaScript, React) | Project Management | Scrum Master

Kuala Lumpur, Federal Territory of Kuala Lumpur, Malaysia

Summary

Experienced on highly competent Application Developer/Support with an Certified Scurm Master with almost 6 Years of experience on React Development as a Senior Software Engineer. I understand the latest project techniques and tools in depth and I am adaptive at all aspects of development from project planning to requirements gathering through to writing and testing code based on the emerging technologies, creating documentation and support application

Experience

FWD Insurance Senior System Analyst August 2023 - Present (1 year 5 months) Kuala Lumpur, Federal Territory of Kuala Lumpur, Malaysia

Led the analysis and design efforts for the front-end of a React Native application, ensuring seamless user experiences for DMS, OWB, and UnderWrite Me modules.

Collaborated with cross-functional teams to gather and document requirements, translating business needs into technical specifications for development.

Played a key role in architecting and implementing a responsive and user-friendly UI for the React Native app, enhancing user interaction and productivity.

Conducted in-depth system analysis and debugging to identify and resolve performance bottlenecks and critical issues in DMS, OWB, and UnderWrite Me components.

Proactively identified opportunities for automation and optimization within the system, leading to improved operational efficiency.

Maybank

6 years 1 month

Senior Software Engineer August 2021 - August 2023 (2 years 1 month) Malaysia

- Developed an application using React.js in accordance with business requirements and provided instructions to develop the application.
- Utilized React Hooks to design and display forms based on the type of elements which reduced development cost by 10%.
- Effectively managed source code and approved source merges, as well as allocated resources and projects to team members.
- Created user interface (UI) components and unit tested with React-Testing-Library for reusability. Implemented React components and optimized current system performance.
- Debugged application and provided support on completed projects.
- Designed and implemented RESTful application programming interfaces
 (API) for better use of application

Software Engineer November 2020 - August 2021 (10 months) Malaysia

- Developed components for web applications using React, Redux, Router and Axios, improving user experience and speed by 15% with no degradation in performance.
- Implemented single-based application architecture to allow multiple-level projects to run without needing changes to front-end code.
- Constructed Redux reducers to store and process incoming server requests and responses, supplying a proper schema defining JSONconvertible fields.
- Utilized React, Redux, and Router libraries to upgrade UI/UX project at Maybank.
- Developed reusable components and unit tests with React-Testing-Library, providing common interfaces for improved performance.
- Utilized Agile methodology to coordinate and collaborate with a remote team of software engineers and developers

UI UX Developer

January 2019 - November 2020 (1 year 11 months)

Kuala Lumpur, Kuala Lumpur, Malaysia

- * Worked on Redux, Routers and React libraries for the new Upgraded UI/UX project at maybank.
- * Created and implemented components for single based application to provide multiple level projects to achieve without change any front end level codes.
- * Provided with proper schema for the fields that can bring through a JSON format with respective to the server side request.
- *Required to utilize the Redux and reducers for the server side responses to be stored and process through front level.
- * Experience in providing best solution to have common interfaces that provided improved in performances.

Junior Developer

January 2018 - January 2019 (1 year 1 month)

Kuala Lumpur, Malaysia

- * Knowledge on System Development Life Cycle process on the working along with the Quality assurance to validate the project works that including to prepare the documents such as Technical specification document, System Integration Testing (included with SIT Test Plan and SIT Test Scripts).
- * Understanding the Review Coding, standard and also working along with the importance on the performance of the project. Increasing the standard of development and also increase the programming techniques according to the latest object-oriented programming structure which resolves the customer experience to an efficiency of the system.
- * Resolving Penetration Testing (Cross site Scripting, Email Spam, Information Exposure), Performing Research and development to find out the best solution to fixes the findings provided by the cyber security department to achieve the Bank Negara Standards.
- * Worked on the Insurance and Banking inter connected API System to facilities customer to renew and purchase their insurance with the partner companies with the bank network system. The architecture of the system recommended and follow the standards of the cyber security division.

Intern

August 2017 - December 2017 (5 months)

Kuala Lumpur, Malaysia

* Understanding the importance of the business and customer related solution to provide the best customer experience and resolving a problem by creating

the solution that can make customer time and money efficiency. Based on the google selection customer able to drive to exact credit to be a target to the respective customer. (Google Analytics and Google Ad words)

- * Working along with current security function and resolving by introducing new standards of coding methodologies. understanding the importance of validation and respective technologies during the internship.
- * Working along with "Central Bank" (Bank Negara) to fixes vulnerabilities raised by the Bank Negara and makes a system to be secure and system correctness.

United Stationers (pvt) ltd. Cashier July 2012 - March 2013 (9 months) Sri Lanka

- Handling traditional billing systems can be provided in the industry of whole sales where technologies don't improve from manual systems to POS (Point of sales systems).
- Understanding the importance of sales and learning new marketing tactics to improvise the business skills to attract customers.
- Opportunity to receive to change quotation handling and communication can be done through via email. SME (Small Medium Enterprises) broadband connection and creating an own Facebook pages and also creating digital marketing opportunities to evolve in the current market.
- Managing the network setup and white listed the companies devices and also provides extensive network setup to provide successful solution to companies and created the first milestone with the technology.

Education

University of Wollongong

Bachelor of Science (BSc), Computer Software Engineering & Digital Systems Security · (2014 - 2016)

Cardiff Metropolitan University

Master of Business Administration - MBA, Business Analytics · (April 2022 - August 2024)

INTI College Subang Jaya
Foundation degree, Information Technology · (2013 - 2014)

Wycherley International School
CAE, GCE Cambridge Advanced Level (Sri Lanka) · (2009 - 2011)

ST. Benedict's College Sri Lanka GCE Ordinary Level (Sri Lanka) · (1999 - 2009)